acustica-audio.com 2019-12-22

# Avant-garde audio plugins for mixing, mastering and sound production - Acustica Audio

During the current month (May, 2018) we are updating our Privacy Policy in order to report in the most transparent way what kind of information we collect and why we do it. Furthermore, we have improved the Privacy Control and other types of controls with a view to safeguard your data and protect your privacy.

We are making these updates at the entry into force of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in the European Union, effective starting from 25 May 2018. Designed to harmonize the privacy laws in force in Europe, the GDPR refines the rules on transparency relating to the way companies disclose their internal data processing. We are making some mandatory updates to our Privacy Policy and we take the opportunity to make improvements aimed at all the users of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. throughout the world.

This Privacy Policy allows you to better understand what data we collect, why we collect them and how you can update, manage, export and delete your information.

**DATA COLLECTED BY ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L.**

We want you to understand the types of information we collect when you use our services.

We collect data to offer better services to all our users. As an example, we need to understand fundamental elements such as the language you speak, or more complex elements such as the products you purchased and the discounts you received, or which products you tried and which ones you might be interested in. This kind of information is included in the form you have filled in the site:

We store information about the products you bought and their purchase price, in addition to the discounts received. We also store the operations you perform while using the Aquarius application, in order to identify problems and to facilitate technical support in case of problems. This stored information helps us to find out if our system is under attack by people who could jeopardize the security of the data we are protecting.

The data collected by ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. and the way they are used depend on how you utilize our services and how you set your privacy controls.

When you are not logged into an ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. account, we store the information we have collected by means of unique identifiers linked to the browser and/or to the applications you are using, such as the Aquarius application.

When you log in, we also collect the data that we store with your account ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., treating them as sensitive personal information.

**Content created or provided to us by you**

When creating an ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. account, you provide personal information that includes your name and password. You can also decide to add a phone number or data related to your private address and your nationality. You can choose to provide us with information even if you do not access an ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. account, for instance, your email address, in order to receive updates about our services.

In some countries, some of these data are required (not just optional) for the purpose of a proper mandatory billing.

We also collect content that you create, upload or receive from others when you use our services, such as Aquarius. This includes, for example, data transmitted to other third-party companies that utilize the Aquarius service or our technical support.

To allow you to use our services without forcing you to re-enter your data each time, we reserve the right to keep your data for a period of at least three years. Remember that you can request cancellation at any time by means of a ticket to our support staff.

**Data we collect when you use our services**

We collect information about Aquarius and the browser you use to access the ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. services; this information helps us to provide features such as automatic product updates.

The data we collect includes unique identifiers, browser type, and settings, operating system type, and settings, as well as the version number of the application. We also collect information about the interaction of Aquarius with our services, including IP address, abnormal termination reports, system activity and the date, time and URL command of your request.

We collect this information whenever a service of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. contacts our servers, for instance when installing a library or when a service checks for automatic updates.

We collect information about your activities within our services, which we use for example to recommend a product or a library that you might like. Information regarding activities may include:

\- Terms you are looking for;

\- Video you watch;

\- The music you listen to;

\- Views and interactions with content and ads;

\- Shopping;

\- People you communicate or share content with;

-  Browsing history.

If you use our services to send or receive messages, we may collect information about the time and date logs of the messages, as well as their content. Some of these services are currently not running on the Aquarius platform, but they will be enabled in the coming months. Our goal is to improve user interaction by allowing to share feedback on various products, such as reviews and ratings.

**WHY ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. COLLECTS DATA**

**We collect data to offer better services.**

We use the data collected by all our services for the following purposes:

1\. Provide our services

We use your data to provide our services, such as processing the terms you seek in order to return relevant results or helping you share content by suggesting you selected recipients chosen from your contacts.

2\. Maintain and improve our services

We also use your information to ensure that our services work as intended, for instance monitoring any service interruption or troubleshooting what you report to us. We also use this information to make improvements to our services. For instance, understanding which search terms refer to a given product allows us to understand which is the majority interest in a possible update.

3\. Develop new services

We use the information collected in the existing services in order to develop new ones. For example, understanding how people have organized their libraries might suggest a better way to present them in a more intuitive fashion for a forthcoming update.

4\. Offer personalized services, including content and ads

We use the information collected to create services tailored to you, for example by offering you advice, personalized content and personalized search results, as well as discounts;

Depending on your settings, we may show you ads that are tailored to your interests. For example, if you search for "tube equalizer", you might see an advertisement related to our Ruby product, or related to a specific Nebula library;

We do not display personalized ads based on sensitive categories such as ethnicity, religion, sexual orientation or health;

We do not share with external advertisers sensitive data such as name or email address that can identify you unless you have given us express permission to do so.

5\. Measure the performance

We use data for internal analysis and measurements, in order to understand the way our services are used. For example, we analyze data about your visits to our website in order to optimize our product design. We also use data about ads you interact with to help advertisers understand the performance of their advertising campaigns.

6\. Communicate with you

We use the information we collect, such as email addresses, to interact directly with you. For example, we may send you a notification if we detect suspicious activity, such as an attempt to access your account in an unusual way by making extraordinary purchases or by improper use of the software. Or we could inform you about the upcoming changes or improvements regarding our services. If you contact ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., we will keep a record of your request in order to help you resolve any further problems that eventually may arise.

7\. Protect ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., our customers and the public

We use the information to improve the security and reliability of our services. This includes the detection, prevention, and response to fraudulent activities, illegal behavior, security risks and technical problems that could damage ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., our users or the public;

We use different technologies to process your data for the indicated purposes. We use automated systems that analyze your content to provide you with, for example, personalized search results, personalized ads or other features modeled on your utilization of our services. We also analyze your content in order to detect any illicit behaviors such as spam, malware, and illegal content.

We will request your consent before using your information for any purpose not explicitly covered by this Privacy Policy.

**PRIVACY CONTROLS AT YOUR DISPOSAL**

You have several options for managing the information we collect and how it is used.

In general, you can contact our technical support directly by means of a ticket and revoke any information that you do not want to share, as well as modify any privacy settings of your account. You can edit some of this information directly from your account, such as changing or removing your personal address. Due to other European regulations, we are still obliged to know at least your nationality and to compare it with the IP address you use to access our services, in order to correctly calculate the VAT. We also need correct data to properly fill out the invoices relating to the European countries in which these are mandatory (B2C).

Within every email received via Aquarius you will have a link to perform the "unsubscribe" operation. In the absence of this link, if you opt to be removed from our services you can temporarily use the regular ticket system, or click on the link on this page. In the event of a re-activation of your account following a previous de-activation, you need to open an appropriate ticket to our technical support.

You can also request to remove content from ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. services specifically according to the applicable law.

In order to delete all your data or your entire account, you may need to open a support ticket.

**DATA SHARING**

When you share data

Some of our services allow you to share data with other people; you can control how this happens.

Please keep in mind that whenever you share information publicly, your content may become accessible through search engines.

When your data are shared by ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L.

We do not share your personal information with other companies, organizations or individuals that are not part of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., except in the following cases:

1\. With the consent of the user

We will share personal information outside of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. only and exclusively with your consent. We will explicitly ask for your consent before sharing any sensitive personal information;

2\. To the administrators of our infrastructures

Our servers are managed by external companies based in Italy. These companies are authorized to solve system problems on our infrastructure. We have ensured that we have received appropriate documentation from them to verify that they fully abide by the new European regulations on privacy. We are cooperating with these partners to increase data security;

3\. To access information stored in your account, such as your email, and keep it;

4\. To visualize statistics related to your account, such as how many libraries you install;

5\. To modify the password of your account;

6\. To suspend or close your account;

7\. To retrieve any account information to comply with current law or regulation, a judicial process or an applicable government request;

8\. To limit your ability to delete or change information or your privacy settings;

9\. To use external payment systems

In this case, we share the minimum set of information required for the correct completion of the receipt by our suppliers. For example, we use the PayPal services to receive and make payments, and we file some data related to the transaction, but we do not receive from them any data related to the means of payment, such as bank accounts and credit card codes;

10\. For legal reasons

We will share personal information outside of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. if we believe in good faith that access to, use, protection or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary in order to:

\- comply with applicable laws or regulations, a judicial proceeding or a mandatory government request. We share information about the number and type of requests we receive from governments in our Transparency Report;

\- enforce the applicable Terms of Service, including investigations regarding potential violations;

\- detect, prevent or otherwise manage fraudulent activities or problems of technical nature or related to safety;

\- protect the rights, property or safety of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., our users or the public, as required or permitted by law.

Wherever ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. was involved in a merger, acquisition or sale of resources, the company will continue to guarantee the confidentiality of your personal information and will communicate to the interested users any transfer of information or the application of different privacy policies.

**PROTECTION OF INFORMATION**

**We are implementing secure services to protect your information**

All ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. products are designed with powerful security features that continuously protect your information. The information we obtain from maintaining our services helps us to automatically detect and block security threats so that users are not involved. If we detect something risky that we believe is appropriate to let you know, we will inform you and help you through, showing you all the steps to make sure you have all the necessary protection.

We are working to protect you and ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. from unauthorized access to information in our possession and from unauthorized alteration, disclosure, and destruction of such information. In particular:

\- We review our practices of gathering, storing and processing information, including physical security measures, to prevent unauthorized access to systems;

\- We allow access to personal information only to employees, contractors, and agents for ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. who need this information to be able to process it.

All persons granted such access must comply with strict contractual obligations regarding confidentiality and may be subject to sanctions or termination of the contract if they do not comply with these obligations.

**COMPLIANCE AND COOPERATION WITH REGULATORS**

We review this Privacy Policy on a regular basis and ensure that we process your information in a manner consistent with it.

**Data transfers**

We operate servers all over the world but your personal information is stored exclusively on servers located in Italy, therefore within the European Community.

In case of necessity (for example relating to reports for third-party developers residing outside the European Community), we guarantee to omit all identifying information of the interested party (address of residence, e-mail address, name, and surname).

In case we receive formal written complaints, we will respond by contacting the person who presented them. We work with the relevant regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any claims related to any transfer of your personal data that can not be resolved directly with you.

**European requirements**

Wherever the European Union Data Protection Act applies to the processing of your information, we will offer the controls described in these policies, so that you can exercise your right to request access, update, removal and limitation of the processing of your information. Furthermore, you have the right to object to the processing of your information or to export it to another service.

We process your information for the purposes described in these rules, based on the following legal reasons:

1\. With the consent of the user

We request your consent to process your information for specific purposes and you have the right to cancel it at any time. For example, we request your consent to provide you with personalized services, such as discounts;

2\. Whenever we pursue legitimate interests

We process your information to pursue our goals and those of third parties, continuing to apply appropriate safeguards to protect your privacy. This means that we process your information, for example, to:

\- Offer, maintain and improve our services and meet users' needs;  
\- Develop new products and features that are useful for our users;  
\- Understand how users utilize our services, to ensure and improve the performance of the aforementioned services;  
\- Customize our services to provide a better user experience;  
\- Make use of marketing strategies to inform users about our services;  
\- Advertise, with a view to making many of our services free and available to users;  
\- Detect, prevent or otherwise manage fraudulent activities, unlawful conduct or problems related to security or technical aspects, in relation to our services;  
\- Protect the rights, property or safety of ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., our users or the public, as required or permitted by law;  
\- Carry out research to improve our services for the users, consequently providing a benefit to the public;  
\- Fulfill obligations to our partners, such as developers and rights holders;  
\- Apply for legal claims, including verification of potential violations of applicable Terms of Service;  
\- Whenever we provide a service;  
\- Whenever we abide by legal obligations.

We will process your data when we have a legal obligation to do so, for example, if we are responding to a judicial proceeding or an enforceable request on behalf of the government.

If you have any questions, please contact ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., namely our data protection officer, reachable by opening a ticket. If you have any concerns regarding your rights under your local law, you should also contact your local data protection authority.

**INFORMATION ON THE PRESENT POLICIES**

**When the policies apply.**

This Privacy Policy applies to all services offered by ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L., and in particular

\- our website [https://www.acustica-audio.com](https://www.acustica-audio.com/)

\- the Aquarius application and its backend system, predisposed to send automated e-mails.

**These policies don't apply to:**

\- The practices relating to the management of information by other companies and organizations that promote our services;

\- Services offered by other companies or individuals, including products or sites that may include ACUSTICAUDIO S.R.L. services, which are displayed in search results or linked by our services.

**Amendments to these policies.**

This Privacy Policy is changed from time to time. We commit ourselves not to limit your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent.

**PRIVACY FOR MINORS**

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 16 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 16. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from children under age 16 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to immediately remove that information from our servers.
